Guide to the New York State College of Agriculture winter short course photographs, 1907-1926.
New York State College of Agriculture winter short course photographs
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
New York State College of Agriculture winter short course photographs, 1907-1926.
21-34-2459
New York State College of Agriculture.
36 items.
Photographs
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Composite photographs and prints of the students and faculty members who attended the winter short courses at Cornell. Composites include the general agriculture, poultry, dairy, and horticulture classes.
ORGANIZATIONAL HISTORY
The first winter short course (Dairy) was given in 1892-93. These courses were provided during the winter to teach practical education to non-traditional students. The courses were inline with Cornell's Land Grant mission. The majority of the students were New York State farmers.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Composite photographs and prints of the students and faculty members who attended the winter short courses at Cornell. Composites include the general agriculture, poultry, dairy, and horticulture classes.
SUBJECTS
Names:
New York State College of Agriculture.; New York State College of Agriculture -- Students.; New York State College of Agriculture -- Faculty.
Form and Genre Terms:
Photographs.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
Items very FRAGILE, handle with care.
RELATED MATERIALS
See also New York State College of Agriculture Winter Short Course Scrapbooks, #21-34-4029.
See also the Michael L. and Catherine H. Whalen Collection of Cornelliana, #37-5-3784.
See also Dairy Industry Winter Course Student Record Cards, #21-19-1190.
CONTAINER LIST
- General Agriculture
  - General Agriculture, Photographer Charles B. Van Buren, print only, 1907 (Map-case Folder 7)
  - General Agriculture, Photographer Charles B. Van Buren, 1908 (Map-case Folder 1)
  - General Agriculture, Photographer Charles B. Van Buren, print, 1908 (Map-case Folder 7)
  - General Agriculture, Winter Course ‘Stone Club’, Photographer Charles B. Van Buren, 1909 (Map-case Folder 1)
  - General Agriculture, Winter Course ‘Stone Club’, Photographer Charles B. Van Buren, print, 1909 (Map-case Folder 7)
  - General Agriculture, Photographer Charles H. Howes, 1910 (Map-case Folder 1)
  - General Agriculture, Photographer Van Buren, 1911 (Map-case Folder 1)
  - General Agriculture, Photographer Van Buren, 1912 (Map-case Folder 2)
  - General Agriculture, Photographer Van Buren, 2 prints, 1912 (Map-case Folder 8)
  - General Agriculture, Photographer Ernest L. Conlon, 1912-13 (Map-case Folder 2)
  - General Agriculture, Photographer Conlon, 1914-15 (Map-case Folder 2)
  - General Agriculture, Photographer Conlon, framed, 1916-17; Framed item
  - See Michael L. and Catherine H. Whalen Collection of Cornelliana, #37-5-3784, item W225., 1918-19
  - General Agriculture, Photographer White Studio, very oversized and framed, 1919-20; Framed item
- Poultry
  - Poultry, James Rice Poultry Club, Photographer Seth L. Sheldon, 1907 (Map-case Folder 4)
  - Poultry, Poultry Husbandry, Photographer Van Buren, 1910 (Map-case Folder 4)
  - Poultry, Winter Poultry Course, no Photographer given, prob. Van Buren, 1910-11 (Map-case Folder 3)
  - Poultry, Winter Poultry Course, Photographer Van Buren, 1911-12 (Map-case Folder 3)
  - Poultry, Winter Course Rice Poultry Club, Photographer Robinson, 1912-13 (Map-case Folder 11)
  - Poultry, Winter Course Rice Poultry Club, Photographer Frederick Robinson, 1913-14 (Map-case Folder 4)
  - Poultry, Winter Course Poultry Husbandry, Photographer Conlon, 1914-15 (Map-case Folder 5)
  - Poultry, Winter Course Poultry Husbandry, Photographer Conlon, 1915-16 (Map-case Folder 5)
  - Poultry, Winter Course Poultry Husbandry, Photographer White, 1916-17 (Map-case Folder 3)
  - Winter Poultry Course, Photographer Koch's studio, 1917-18 (Map-case Folder 5)
  - Winter Course, (probably Poultry) Photographer Van Buren, 1918-19 (Map-case Folder 5)
  - Poultry Winter Course, Photographer Van Buren, 1919-20 (Map-case Folder 6)
  - Poultry Winter Course, Photographer Van Buren, 1921-22 (Map-case Folder 6)
  - Poultry Winter Course, Photographer Van Buren, 1924-25 (Map-case Folder 6)
  - Poultry Winter Course, Photographer R. Tompkins, 1925-26 (Map-case Folder 6)
- Dairy
  - Dairy School, Photographer Sheldon, print only, 1905 (Map-case Folder 9)
  - Dairy School, Photographer Van Buren, print only, 1906 (Map-case Folder 9)
  - Winter Dairy Course, Photographer S. L. Sheldon, 1912-13 (Map-case Folder -)
  - Winter Dairy Course, Photographer S. L. Sheldon, 1913-14 (Map-case Folder -)
  - Winter Dairy Course, Photographer R. G. Estabrook, 1914-15 (Map-case Folder -)
- Horticulture
  - Horticulture, Photographer Van Buren, print only, 1909 (Map-case Folder 9)
  - Horticulture Winter Short Course, composite photo by Comlon, 1914-1915 (Map-case Folder 9)
- Unknown or loose photos
  - 8 portraits pasted on one poster, Undated (Map-case Folder 10)
    Dr. E.M. Santee, Wellsboro, NY
    S.L. Cole, Oneonta, NY
    John D. Jaquins, Watervliet, NY
    John Jeannin, West Sand Lake, NY
    Dr. Stanley Merckley, Buffalo, NY
    Jacob P. Miller, Syracuse, NY
    Robert Seamon, Hicksville, NY
    I.H. Whitmyre, Schenectady, NY
  - Composite, 57 portraits, incl. two women, Prof. James Rice, Photographer Van Buren, 1924 (Map-case Folder 3)
  - Photographer C.H. Howes, includes Liberty Bailey, Prof. Rice, Miss C Nixon, assistant, Undated (Map-case Folder 3)